In the last lecture, we added the sideDrawer
W ostatnim wykadzie mielimy przy bocznych drzwiach.
and of course this is looking horrible because logo and navigation items need to be adjusted to look good
I oczywicie to wyglda okropnie, poniewa logo i elementy nawigacyjne musz by dostosowane, by
on mobile devices.
dobrze wyglday na urzdzeniach mobilnych.
Let's start with the logo, it
Zacznijmy od logo.
right now is so big because the logo height is set to 80% and 80% in the sideDrawer means
Obecnie jest tak dua, poniewa wysoko logo jest ustawiona na 80 procent, a 80 procent w
80% of the full sizeDrawer height here,
bocznej szufladzie oznacza 80 procent penej wysokoci derecho.
that of course is a little bit too much.
To oczywicie troch za duo.
Now how can we adjust this? We could add some responsive design to the logo.css
Teraz, jak moemy si dostosowa, poniewa moemy doda reakcj projektu na logo.
file, we could set the default to something like 11% and add a media query to wrap this up
Zobacz plik s moe ustawi warto domyln na okoo 11 procent i doda zapytanie o media, aby zawin to do
to 80% for bigger screens
80 procent w przypadku wikszych ekranw.
but that would make our logo harder to reuse. Instead
Ale to uczynioby nasze logo trudniejszym w uyciu.
I'm a fan of controlling the logo height in the place where we embed it instead of in the logo component.
Jestem fanem kontrolowania DILG a Hyatt w miejscu, w ktrym si osadzilimy, zamiast w komponencie logo.
So I actually will even set the logo height back to 100% and we should restrict its height in the
Tak wic nawet ustawi logo z powrotem na 100 procent i powinnimy ograniczy jego wysoko w
toolbar and in the sideDrawer to fit the specific needs of these components.
pasku narzdzi iw bocznej szufladzie, aby dopasowa si do konkretnych potrzeb tych komponentw.
So let's start with the toolbar,
Zacznijmy od paska narzdzi.
as I said, the logo should only be 80% high here,
Jak ju powiedziaem, logo powinno by wysokie tylko o 80 procent.
we can achieve this in two ways. We could add a prop to actually set the height dynamically so we could
Moemy to osign na dwa sposoby, dziki czemu moemy doda podprk, aby faktycznie ustawi wysoko dynamicznie, abymy
add something like height here which we could set to let's say 80%
mogli doda co takiego, jak wysoko, co moemy ustawi na przykad na 80 procent.
and then in the logo, we can accept this,
I to w logo moemy zaakceptowa.
we do accept props here and we could set inline styles here to overwrite the css class settings, to
Akceptujemy tutaj rekwizyty i moglibymy tutaj ustawi style wewntrzne, aby nadpisa ustawienia klasy C S S,
basically assign a javascript object here where we set height to props.height.
aby zasadniczo przypisa obiekt javascript, w ktrym ustawiamy wysoko na wysoko rekwizytw.
If we save this, it should now look good in the toolbar still and if we do that in the sideDrawer too, there
Jeli to zapiszemy, powinno to wyglda dobrze na pasku narzdzi, a jeli zrobimy to w cydrze lub
we would also now simply pass a height to the logo,
dwch, to po prostu przekaemy wysoko logotypowi.
let's say not props,
Powiedzmy, e nie ma rekwizytw.
height should be 11% here,
Powinno wynosi 11 procent rocznie.
now it should look good in a sideDrawer too.
Teraz powinna dobrze wyglda rwnie w bocznej szufladzie.
This is one clever way of adjusting this, setting the height as a property where we simply pass the percentage
Jest to sprytny sposb dostosowania tego ustawienia wysokoci jako waciwoci, w ktrej po
height to the logo component and in the component, assign it dynamically via inline styles.
prostu przekazujemy procentow wysoko do komponentu logo, a nastpnie komponent przypisuje j dynamicznie wyinaczy style.
Nothing wrong with this approach, it should work fine,
Nic zego w tym podejciu powinno dziaa dobrze.
I want to show you an alternative to that though.
Chc ci jednak pokaza alternatyw.
I'll actually leave that property set up here so that we could use that
Zostawi t waciwo tutaj, ebymy mogli z niej skorzysta.
but I will not use it,
Ale nie uyj tego.
I will instead follow a different approach and wrap logo into a div in the sideDrawer and also in the
Zamiast tego zastosuj inne podejcie i zawi logo w div na pasku bocznym, a take na pasku
toolbar,
narzdzi.
so let's wrap logo into a div in both components and not use this.height property which again just to
Wic zawimy logo do elementu div w obu komponentach i nie uywajmy. Czy waciwo height, ktra ponownie wystarczy,
highlight this would not have been a bad approach at all.
aby to podkreli, nie byaby wcale zym podejciem.
And now these divs which wrap the logo, they should control the height,
A teraz te rnice, ktre zawijaj logo, powinny kontrolowa wysoko.
we can do this with inline styles or with a css class like
Moemy to zrobi za pomoc stylw rdliniowych lub z ozami jako podobiestwa klas.
for example here in the toolbar classes logo and the cool thing is I can now use the logo class here
Na przykad tutaj s dwa logo klas supkowych i fajne jest to, e mog uy klasy logo
the toolbar component even though I'm already using it in the logo component because due to css modules,
w tym komponencie paska narzdzi, mimo e ju go uywam w komponencie logo, poniewa postrzegasz nas jako moduy.
it will convert
To moe dziaa.
my css class names into different names and to scope names, so that even though I write two identical
Moje C to nazwy klas w rnych nazwach i nazwach zakresu, tak wic nawet jeli pisz dwie
classes in the development mode here, it actually converts that to two different css classes which
identyczne klasy w trybie rozwoju, to faktycznie mona je wymwi do dwch rnych klas C S S,
get assigned so that they don't interfere.
ktre s przypisane tak, aby nie przeszkadzay.
So now I can define that logo class in my toolbar and there, I can set height to 80% and I can now
Wic znajduj t klas logo na pasku narzdzi i mog ustawi wysoko na 80 procent i mog teraz przej do
go to the sideDrawer and there, I can also define a logo class and set the height to 11% here.
szuflady witryny i tam mog rwnie zdefiniowa klas logo i ustawi tutaj wysoko 11 procent, a
And now I can use that here in the sideDrawer and assign my class name there too
teraz mog uy tutaj w bocznej szufladzie i tam te przypisz moje nazwisko.
so also set classes.Logo here. And again, I do have that logo class defined in three different files
Wic wszystkie klasy aktyww loguj si tu i znowu, mam t klas logo, ktr mona znale w trzech rnych plikach.
but due to css modules, this is actually converted to three different css classes so that they don't interfere.
Ale widzisz, e moduy faktycznie przeksztacaj si w darmowe rnice jako klasy, aby nie kolidoway ze
With all these changes saved,
wszystkimi zapisanymi zmianami.
we have a nice looking logo here in the sideDrawer and in the toolbar.
Mamy adne logo w szufladzie witryny i pasku narzdzi.
So you saw different approaches of adjusting this dynamically and making sure that it looks good on
Widzielicie wic rne podejcia do dynamicznego dostosowywania i upewniania si, e wszystko wyglda dobrze
all the devices we need to support.
na wszystkich urzdzeniach, ktre musimy obsugiwa.
Let's next work on the navigation items then.
Nastpna praca nad elementem nawigacyjnym isten.